Alex Christianson

5289 Fairview Drive• Stevens Point, 54481

Phone: (715) 540-6321 • E-Mail: alex.christianson.05@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-christianson-90a946217



Summary

I am an aspiring web developer with a Full-Stack Coding Certificate from the University of Wisconsin. While working to earn my certificate, I used many of the skills I had refined during my 10 years as an educator such as time management, leadership, problem solving, and communication.

Experience

Middle School Teacher

2012-Spring 2021

- 7th year as a teacher at Auburndale Middle/High School
- Teach 6th grade Science, Language Arts, and 7th grade Reading
- Member of Academic Career Planning committee and District Leadership Committee

Middle School Teacher

2011-2012

- One year as a middle school teacher at Ladysmith Middle School
- Taught 7th grade Math and 8th grade Science.
- Supervised many co-curricular events and advised/directed Drama Club

Skills

Git/GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScriptMongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, PWAs

Education

UW-Extended Campus Coding Boot Camp

- -August 2021-February 2022
 - Full-Stack Coding Certificate

UW-Oshkosh - June 2015-December 2016

 Master of Science in Education Administration with Principal Licensure Certificate

UW-Stevens Point -Fall 2005-Spring 2011

 Bachelor of Science with a Major in Elementary Education with Minors in both Natural Science and Mathematics

Projects

Reel Roulette

- Application designed to help a user decide what to watch. After a genre is chosen, a movie is displayed with a description and watchable trailer.
- HTML, JavaScript, CSS, and Server-Side APIs

Game Spot Blog

- Blog designed for users to view posts about their favorite games. Upon signing up/logging in, users can post, comment and see a personalized dashboard containing their posts.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, Handlebars.js